Adult Education Research Conference Records
Adult Education Research Conference Records
1964-1971
Adult Education Research Conference
1.5 linear feet
Correspondence, programs, abstracts, drafts. Much of the material is related to the 12th annual conference in 1971
2458601
Biographical History
The Adult Education Research Conference was originally the National Seminar on Adult Education Research, organized in 1960 as a forum for adult education researchers to share research ideas and materials. After meeting annually for six years, it adopted the AERC name and a more formal structure. The 12th annual Adult Education Research Conference, which much of the collection revolves around, was held in New York in 1971.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Adult Education Research Conference Records contains conference material, correspondence, and general files. Conference files contain correspondence on arrangements for the conference, evaluations of the conference submitted by the participants, lists of registrants, and other data. Correspondence includes symposia and executive committee material. Correspondents whose letters are of the greatest number and depth include Virginia Griffin, Arden Grotelueschen, Roy J. Ingham, Allen Menlo, and Allen Tough. General files include letterheads, memoranda, abstracts of papers, and programs.
Related Material
Roy Ingham Papers
The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Bruce, Robert L.; Copeland, Harlan G.; Griffin, Virginia (Virginia R.); Grotelueschen, Arden D.; Ingham, Roy John, 1925-; Menlo, Allen; Tough, Allen M.; Adult Education Research Conference.; National Seminar on Adult Education Research.; Adult education.; Adult education -- Research.; Adult education teachers -- Training of.; Continuing education.; Abstracts (summaries); Correspondence.; Drafts (documents); Mailing lists.; Memorandums.; Programs (documents); Adult education teachers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Conference files
  - Abstracts, 1971 (Box 1)
  - By-laws, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Evaluation sheets, undated (Box 1)
  - File card index (Box 2)
  - General files, correspondence and printed material, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Mailing lists, undated (Box 1)
  - Program, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Registrants, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - ERIC symposia, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Executive committee, 1968-1970 (Box 3)
  - General correspondence
    - 1964-1970 (Box 3)
    - 1968-1971 (Box 3)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Paper rejection, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Session chairman, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
- General files
  - Citations, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Executive committee meeting, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Form letter drafts, undated (Box 3)
  - Letterhead (Box 3)
  - Menlo, Allen, 1968-1970 (Box 3)
  - Minneapolis Chamber of Commerce, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Paper abstracts, 1969? (Box 3)
  - Paper selection criteria sheets, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Paper session programs, 1970 (Box 3)